Anthony Santiago

Lead Software Engineer - Synced Software LLC

Oaklyn, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Anthony-Santiago/212c9154ead14a16

When I was a kid I always enjoyed building things and learning how technologies worked. This was especially true when I discovered the Source Engine through Half-Life 2 and Garry's Mod 9.0.4 at the age of 10. I quickly became immersed in Source SDK and started creating maps for the Source Engine.

If we fast forward to modern day, I basically do the same thing except with code. Like level design, code is a work of art; it tells a story.

0 months into programming I learned the basics of Java and Object Oriented Programming through Oracle's Java Tutorials. To get the most out of my learning, I set off to build a simple musical scale viewer, which would eventually turn into a small scale Swing application.

6 months in I had the knowledge to create an encryption algorithm, convert Swing UI to JavaFX UI, and understand many Object Oriented Programming concepts on a deep level such as Polymorphism. By this time I had also experimented with several other languages such as JavaScript, Lua, C, C++, and Ruby.

12 months in I had successfully created a mobile game using Unity3D and C# that utilized in-app purchases, leaderboards, and achievements. By this time I had experimented with native Android applications. This also marks my transition from simply sitting down and coding to planning things out using UML.

18 months in I enrolled in the Android Developer Nanodegree even though I did not meet the pre-requesite for having 2 years of Java experience. By this time I had experimented with low level concepts using x86 assembler and basic RISC assembler.

24 months in I completed the Android Developer Nanodegree with most projects "exceeding specifications". For my final project I wrote a basic x86 Assembly simulator that teaches programming. At this point I started to transition to using unit testing.

Present day, I still have the mindset to learn something new each and everyday. I aim to create quality software where ever my path takes me.

Udacity Portfolio: https://profiles.udacity.com/u/anthonysantiago

Github: https://github.com/izodine

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/santiagoanthony

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Synced Software LLC - Oaklyn, NJ - April 2014 to Present

I am responsible for all software tasks. This includes but is not limited to designing networks of classes and implementing them. I am also

responsible for mobile development. I have done all of the programming and audio design for our game HexVok which is now on Google Play and

Amazon.

Cashier

Target - Cherry Hill, NJ - November 2015 to December 2015

Responsibilities

I was responsible for processing various payments, price adjustment, and providing good customer service.

Skills Used

Cash Register, Communication, Problem Solving, Basic Mathematics

Toll Collector

Delaware River Port Authority - Pennsauken, NJ - June 2015 to September 2015

I was responsible for collecting fares of various vehicle classes, as well as providing discounts to Patco, Delaware River Port Authority, and bridge

contractors. This required decent communication skills and money management.

EDUCATION

Diploma in General Studies

Collingswood High School 2011 to 2014

SKILLS

Java (2 years), C/C++ (1 year), x86 Assembly(NASM) (Less than 1 year), Android Development (2 years), Audio Production/Music Composition (3 years), JavaScript (Less than 1 year), HTML (Less than 1 year), PHP (Less than 1 year), ActionScript (Less than 1 year), TI Basic (1 year), Micrisoft Tools (1 year), PhoneGap (Less than 1 year), Unity3D (1 year), C#/.NET (1 year), Cash Management, Cash Register

LINKS

http://www.amazon.com/Synced-Software-HexVok/dp/B012LV9J20/ref=sr 1 1? ie=UTF8&qid=1443040929&sr=8-1&keywords=hexvok

https://github.com/izodine

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.syncedsoftware.iassembly

 $\underline{\text{https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=izodine.hexvok\&hl=en}}$

https://profiles.udacity.com/u/anthonysantiago

AWARDS

Outstanding Music Performance

May 2014

Awarded a trophy for writing a piece for Orchestra, and playing it at an orchestra concert.

CERTIFICATIONS

Android Developer Nanodegree

February 2016 to Present

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills

- Microsoft Tools
- Experienced in Java
- Android Development
- C# Experience
- TI Basic Experience
- PHP Experience
- MySQL Experience
- Prior practice with HTML
- Familiar with C/C++
- Experienced in Unity3D
- Audio Design/Production
- Basic x86 Assembly(NASM)
- Basic RISC Assembly